

SUMMERY

Passionate hard-working data science explorer and IT professional with good amount of knowledge and skills in programming, data analysis, data science and machine learning, web and android app development. Worked with many startups as well as well-known companies providing IT solutions for them. I love to learn new things, experiment and challenge acquired skills. I am also winner of multiple programming and general science olympiads in Bangladesh.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Skills:

Python

Excel

SQL

NumPy Pandas

Matplotlib

PowerBI Tableau

SAS Visual

. ,		
R		
Java		
С		
Machine L Tensorflow	<u>earning Skills:</u>	
Scikit Learn		
Keras		
Pycaret		
Data Related Skills:		

AZMINE TOUSHIK WASI

WORK EXPERIENCE

Content Designer

!0 Minute School June 20, 2021 - Present

Work Details:

- Inforgrapher: K!2 Project, Designer: BCS Preparation
- Book Designer and Content Researcher

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE (VOLUNTEER)

Executive Officer of Operations Management

Black Brains

July 2021 – Present (Working here since December 2020)

Work Details:

- Redesigned Black Brains website and tasks given to the interns
- Created 200+ graphical contents for many events
- Administrated central database

Central Database Administrator

Bangladesh Youngster Social Organization July 2020 – June 2021

Work Details:

- BYSO App Development, Deployment and Maintenance
- Central Database Administration
- Developing IT Structure for the organization

Judge, The Queens Commonwealth Essay Competition 2021

The Royal Commonwealth Society

July 2021 – August 2021

Work Details:

 Member of the judging panel of the competition with 26,000_ submission

Online Volunteer

United Nations Volunteers September 2019 – April 2021

Work Details:

- Data based online projects
- Graphics designing support

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Engg.) in Industrial and Production Engineering

Shahjalal University Of Science And Technology Expected to complete in 2023

Higher Secondary Certificate

Comilla Shikkha Board Model College Science | 2019 | Result : GPA 5.00

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIPS

Engineering: Undergraduate & Masters Forage – Microsoft | June 2021

Completed tasks on:

- · Software Engineering, Design, Engineering thinking
- · Data Analytics , Business Modeling

Data@ANZ Program Forage - ANZ | March 2021

Completed tasks on:

- Data Science (Used Scikitlearn Linear Regression)
- Exploratory Data Analysis Predictive Analytics

Open-Access Data Science & Advanced Analytics Forage – BCG | April 2021

Completed tasks on:

- · Data Science and Problem Structuring
- · EDA, Feature Engineering, Mathematical Modeling

Digital Technology Data Analytics Program Forage - General Electric | April 2021

Completed tasks on:

- Data Preparing and Exploratory Data Analysis
- · Feature Engineering, Machine Learning

Data Science and Business Analytics Intern The Sparks Foundation - GRIP | June 2021

Completed tasks on:

- · Problem Structuring and Business Modeling
- · EDA,, Mathematical Modeling

Engineering Virtual Program Forage - Goldman Sachs / April 2021

Completed tasks on:

· Data Analysis

ONLINE COURSES & PROGRAMS

Professional Certificates (Coursera):

- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer
- SAS Visual Business Analytics

Google Career - Professional Certificates (Coursera):

- IT Automation with Python, IT Support Professional
- Project Management, Data Analyst

Edx Courses:

- IBMx DS0105EN: Data Science Tools
- Harvardx PH526x: Using Python for Research

Coursera Specializations Completed:

- Python 3 Programming
- Applied Data Science with Python

LinkedIn Learning Paths Completed:

• Software Developer, Data Analyst, Financial Analyst

IBM Developer Skills Network Programs:

- Data and AI CP4D Journey Intermediate
- Python for Data Science Program

Sololearn Courses Completed:

- Data Science, Machine Learning
- · Python Core, Python for Data Science

OTHER SKILLS

MS Word, MS Powerpoint,
MS Access, MS Excel
Web Design, HTML-CSS, PHP,
Wordpress – Elementor
G-Suite, Google Analytics
Adobe Illustrator, Canva,
Adobe Photoshop
Content Writing, Script Writing,
Communication, Teamwork,
Proficient in Bangla and English

PRIZES AND AWARDS

- National High School Programming Contest – 2016 and 2017 – Regional Winner; National Top 30 in both
- Inter School and College Programming Contest 2019 – Regional 3rd - National Top 30
- Queens Commonwealth Essay Competition 2019 – Silver Award
- National Earth Science Olympiad
 2019 National Winner
- Bangladesh Physics Olympiad '19 Comilla Region - 5th
- Bangladesh Chemistry Olympiad
 '19 Comilla Region -1st Place

HOBBY

Reading Books, Rubics Cube, Solving Puzzles, Diary Writing, Drawing, Sketching.

CONTACT INFORMATION

- Comilla, Bangladesh
- +880-1521-526792
- azminetoushik.wasi@gmail.com
- /x.azmine.wasi
- in /azmine-toushik-wasi
- /AzmineWasi
- /azminewasi
- Azminewasi.github.io
- /XioxosticCreations